Guide to the Coleman Dowell Papers 1925-1985 MSS 036
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Accretion 2008 - Series II: Published and Unpublished Works
  All folders containing excerpts from Dowell's journals are restricted until 31 December 2010.
  - An American Eccentric [annotated draft] (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - An American Eccentric [annotated draft: Descriptive Writing], undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - An American Eccentric [annotated draft: Noteworthy Events], undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - An American Eccentric [annotated draft: Observations], undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - An American Eccentric [annotated draft: Personality Characteristics and Quirks], undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - An American Eccentric [annotated drafts: Physical Health], undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - An American Eccentric [annotated draft: Relationship with Doug], undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - An American Eccentric [annotated draft: Romantic and/or Social Involvements], undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - An American Eccentric [annotated draft: Suicidal Thoughts], undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - An American Eccentric [annotated drafts: Writings], undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - An American Eccentric [annotated journal], 1977-1984 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - An American Eccentric [journal fragments], 1970-1984 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - An American Eccentric [journal manuscript pp. i-v, 1-130], 1964-1974 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - An American Eccentric [journal manuscript pp. 131 - 307], 1974-1984 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - An American Eccentric [supplemental and administrative materials], 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Cole and Tam - A Writer and His Dog [manuscripts and correspondence], 1990 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - A Dark Book / A Star-Bright Lie [correspondence], 1987, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - "Der Junge Knecht" - German translation of "Ham's Gift" by Ruth Landskoff-Yorck, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous Book Reviews, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Miscellaneous Writings, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - The Party [manuscript and correspondence], 1993 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - The Party [manuscript and correspondence], 1993 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Posthumous clippings and excerpts [writings and journals], 1987-1994 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - "Reading of Astrological Chart by Isidor Oblo...", 1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Suicide Note, Last Will and Testament, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - "The Writing of The Silver Swanne", undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Accretion 2008 - Series III: Musical Works and Lyrics
  Accretion 2008 Series II contains handwritten and annotated sheet music, primarily from The Tattooed Countess.
  - Maybe I'll Leave You, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - So Long - Vincenzo, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Some Sugar Morning, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Tattooed Countess, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Think I'll Fall in Love Tonight, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Accretion 2008 - Series IV: Works by Others and Miscellaneous Materials
  Arrangement note
  The contents of folders in this series reflect the original order in which materials were kept by Bertram Slaff.
  This series contains works by other writers and various materials related to Dowell's life and career. The three folders of photographic materials contain photographic prints, contact sheets, and negative film.
  - Arlen, Doug: Private! Keep Out!, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Arlen, Doug: Two Men, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Coleman Dowell "Memorabilia", undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Contains clippings and writings by or about Dowell, compiled by Bertrand Slaff.
  - Copyright, "Maybe I'll Leave You", 1972 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Kentucky Education Association - Miscellaneous Materials, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Contains materials related to Simpson County High School reunion, as well as a profile of Dowell published in KEA News.
  - Photocopies - Photos of Dowell's Ancestors, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Photographic Materials (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Photographic Materials (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Photographic Materials (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Royalty Statements, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Slaff, Bertram: Book Review, undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Slaff, Bertram: Irv Bauer, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Slaff, Bertram: Reminiscences About Coleman Dowell, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Slaff, Bertram: The Snake's House, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Tarn, Nathaniel: The Desert Mothers, "Seeing America First", undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Accretion 2008 - Series V: Media
  This series contains one audio CD featuring recordings of Dowell singing some of his songs.
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    Access Copies may not be available. Please consult a Fales Archivist.
  - Subseries B: Originals
    - "Coleman Dowell Sings" CD-R, undated (Box 2, Folder 5, Media ID: 036.0001)
- Accretion 2008 - Oversize Series III: Musical Works and Lyrics
  - The Tattooed Countess, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Opened to Public 2011 - Series I: Correspondence
  Scope and Content
  This portion of correspondence was sealed until 2011, at the request of the collection donor.
  - To: Aman, Madeleine, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - From: Dennis, Efraim, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - From: Holub, Robert, undated
  - From: Misenti, Vincent, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - From: Misenti, Vincent, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - To: Slaff, Bert, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - From: Smith, Hubert E., undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - To: Smith, Hubert E., undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Opened to Public 2011 - Series VI: Journal
  This series consists of Dowell's typescript journals; access to this material was restricted until 2011, at the request of the collection donor.
  - Journal, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Journal, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Journal, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Journal, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Journal, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Journal, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Journal, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Journal, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Journal, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Journal, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Journal, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Journal, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Journal, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Journal, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - [Journal] miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)